<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<executable>

  <category>Registration</category>
    <title>Atlas-builder</title>
    <description>Longitudinal atlas-building</description>
    <version>1.0</version>
    <documentation-url></documentation-url>
    <license>Apache 2.0</license>
    <contributor>The CALATK team</contributor>
    <acknowledgements></acknowledgements>

  <parameters>
        <label>Computational settings</label>
        <description>Adjusts main settings for the computation</description>

        <integer>
            <name>iDimension</name>
            <label>Image Dimension</label>
            <flag>d</flag>
            <longflag>--dimension</longflag>
            <constraints>
                <minimum>0</minimum>
                <maximum>3</maximum>
                <step>1</step>
            </constraints>
            <default>0</default>
            <description>Specifies explicitly the dimension of the used images. If not specified, the image dimension is guessed. However, this can lead to ambiguities for vector-valued images.</description>
        </integer>

        <string-enumeration>
            <name>sFloatingPointType</name>
            <label>Floating point type</label>
            <flag>t</flag>
            <longflag>--type</longflag>
            <default>float</default>
            <element>float</element>
            <element>double</element>
            <description>Specifies the floating point type for the computations (float/double). In general float is recommended (because it will save memory). If CALATK is not compiled to support floating point choice, this option is ignored.</description>
        </string-enumeration>

  </parameters>

  <parameters>
        <label>Input/Output</label>
        <description>Input/Output Parameters</description>

        <file>
          <name>configFileData</name>
          <longflag>--configData</longflag>
          <label>Data configuration file</label>
          <default>None</default>
          <description>JSON Configuration file to specify the data. If given source images are specified in this file. Atlas will be declared as target image if the images are given at time point 0 and as source image if they are given at time point 0.</description>
        </file>

	<file>
	  <name>configFile</name>
	  <longflag>--config</longflag>
	  <label>Configuration file</label>
	  <default>None</default>
	  <description>JSON Configuration file.</description>
	</file>

	<file>
	  <name>configFileOutPrefix</name>
	  <longflag>--configOutPrefix</longflag>
	  <label>Resulting configuration file prefix</label>
	  <default>None</default>
	  <description>JSON Configuration file prefix which describes the full parameterization of the algorithm run. Will create multiple json-files, as this is a hierarchical configuration pointing to multiple files.</description>
	</file>

        <boolean>
          <name>bCleanJSONConfigOutput</name>
          <longflag>--cleanConfigOutput</longflag>
          <default>false</default>
          <description>If set a config file written out with --configOut will only contain values that are actually used within a run. This is useful when using a pre-specified configuration file with --config to extract only the relevant settings. Otherwise missing settings are simply added (which can also be useful if one would like to store multiple settings, e.g., for different kernels. etc. in one configuration file).
          </description>
        </boolean>

        <string-enumeration>
            <name>sCleanedConfigurationType</name>
            <label>Cleaned Configuration Type</label>
            <longflag>--cleanedConfigurationType</longflag>
            <default>normal</default>
            <element>normal</element>
            <element>advanced</element>
            <element>expert</element>
            <description>Selects how much information the cleaned output should contain. Normal should be sufficient for the beginning user, advanced will expose some specialized options, and expert will show them all. Use this in combination with --cleanConfigOutput to generate initial configuration levels of various complexities.</description>
        </string-enumeration>

        <boolean>
          <name>bCreateJSONHelp</name>
          <longflag>--createJSONHelp</longflag>
          <default>false</default>
          <description>If set, will generate annotated settings in the JSON configuration file. This is to help understand the meaning and options of the different settings.</description>
        </boolean>

        <boolean>
          <name>bOnlyComputePopulationAtlasForFirstAvailableTimePoint</name>
          <longflag>--onlyComputePopulationAtlasForFirstAvailableTimePoint</longflag>
          <default>false</default>
          <description>If set, maps are only computed to allow to map to the first time-point of the population atlas.</description>
        </boolean>

        <boolean>
          <name>bOnlyComputePopulationAtlasForLastAvailableTimePoint</name>
          <longflag>--onlyComputePopulationAtlasForLastAvailableTimePoint</longflag>
          <default>false</default>
          <description>If set, maps are only computed to allow to map to the last time-point of the population atlas.</description>
        </boolean>

        <boolean>
          <name>bUseWeightedAveragesForIndividualGrowthModelTimePoints</name>
          <longflag>--useWeightedAverages</longflag>
          <default>false</default>
          <description>If set, computations for specific time-points will be done with weighted averages with respect to the closest measurements points. Weighting is linear. Only affects cross-sectional atlas-building results.</description>
        </boolean>

        <boolean>
          <name>bWriteDesiredComputationsToFileWithoutComputation</name>
          <longflag>--doNotCompute</longflag>
          <default>false</default>
          <description>If set, runs through all the steps and records them without doing any actual computations.</description>
        </boolean>

        <boolean>
          <name>bUsePrecomputedIndividualGrowthModels</name>
          <longflag>--usePrecomputedIndividualGrowthModels</longflag>
          <default>false</default>
          <description>If set, uses the results for the individual growth models which have been computed manually or by a previous run. Requires consistent file names.</description>
        </boolean>

        <boolean>
          <name>bUsePrecomputedCrossSectionalAtlases</name>
          <longflag>--usePrecomputedCrossSectionalAtlases</longflag>
          <default>false</default>
          <description>If set, uses the results for the cross sectional atlases which have been computed manually or by a previous run. Requires consistent file names.</description>
        </boolean>

        <boolean>
          <name>bUsePrecomputedPopulationGrowthModel</name>
          <longflag>--usePrecomputedGrowthModel</longflag>
          <default>false</default>
          <description>If set, uses the results for the population growth model which has been computed manually or by a previous run. Requires consistent file names.</description>
        </boolean>


  </parameters>
</executable>
